A Guide to the University of Virginia School of Medicine Awards, 1967-
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
University of Virginia School of Medicine Awards 1967-
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-45
1 box, 5"x10.5"x15.5," 0.4 feet, 11 folders
Historical Collections
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The files were given by Allison Innes from the School of Medicine Student Affairs Office.
Scope and Content
This collection contains information related to awards given to faculty and students of the School of Medicine. Many of the awards are described. Many winners, but not all, are listed. The first folder, containing award information by year, concerns current and discontinued awards. The following folders contain information on awards that have been discontinued. Information on current awards can be accessed at http://www.med-ed.virginia.edu/handbook/awards/index.cfm.
Arrangement
Following the first folder which contains award information by year, the files are arranged alphabetically by the award name.
Contents List
- Awards by year, 1971-85, TDs (Box-folder 001-001)
  The awards given are: Robert Bennett Bean Teaching Award, James Ernest Kindred Teaching Award, Robley Dunglison Teaching Award, Scholarship Award, Leadership Award, C. Richard Bowman Scholarship Award, Douglas W. Eastwood Anesthesiology Award, Amparo Villar-Palasi Pharmacology Award, James R. Cash Pathology Book Award, Medical Alumni Association Outstanding Student Award, Out-of-Town Attending Award, CIBA Award for Community Service, Upjohn Leadership Award, Merck Manual Awards, Sandoz Scholarship Award, American Medical Women's Association Janet M. Glasgow Memorial Scholarship Award, American Medical Women's Association Scholarship Achievement Citation, Medical Alumni Association Outstanding Student Award, Scholarship Award - School of Medicine, Student Fellowship Research Awards, Byrd S. Leavell Hematology Award, Mosby Book Award, Lange Book Award, and History of Medicine Essay Prize.
- American Medical Women's Association, 1982-2006, TDs, some with AN (Box-folder 001-000)
  American Medical Women's Association Janet M. Glasgow Memorial Scholarship Award and Citation, continued as the AMWA Glasgow-Rubin Achievement Award and Citations
- Byrd S. Leavell Hematology Award, 1973-75, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- Excellence in Emergency Medicine Award, 1990-99, TDs, some with AN (Box-folder 001-000)
- John Horsley Memorial Prize, 1967-68, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- Lange Book Award, 1971-89, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- McGraw Hill Book Award, 1986-2003, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- Merck Manual Awards, 1976-2001, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- Mosby Book Awards, 1972-85, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- Student Fellowship Research Award, 1973-74, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)
- Yoder Mentoring Award, 1997-2000, TDs (Box-folder 001-000)